Sean Menz

Manufacturing Engineer - Lockheed Martin Space Systems Company

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Sean-Menz/24fc603437adb424

Highly efficient and effective engineer with experience in design and manufacture of satellite components. Focused on cost reduction and schedule commitments while producing high quality communication satellites for myriad of clients thru production flow improvement, standardization and process improvement. Work across programs, business units and business functions to deliver customer satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manufacturing Engineer

Lockheed Martin Space Systems Company - Newtown, PA - October 2007 to Present

Liaison between manufacturing shop floor and design engineering supporting the build of multimillion dollar Antenna subsystems for Commercial and Government customers

- Team member in charge of manufacturing support for Antenna Range Fixture purchase which reduced setup time by 33% and cost by 51%
- Lead team member in the design and manufacturing of Antenna components for seven launched satellites, including MUOS Flights 1 and 2.
- Developed new processes for assembly of state of the art Antenna design including component bonds, test setups and rework of vendor hardware to meet engineering and system requirements.
- Developed Production flow used during assembly and testing of Antenna components for variety of customers including US Armed Forces (Navy and Air Force) and foreign customers (VNPT, SKY Perfect JSAT Corporation)
- Lead engineer responsible for non-flight equipment flow from requirements generation thru procurement and floor use.
- Initiated standard fixtures used from start of production to hardware shipment reducing risk to deliverable hardware and fixture cost.
- Designed standard tooling used in assembly and testing of critical Antenna components.
- Participated in reviews to promote ease of production/manufacturability with flight drawing, test procedures, fixtures and test setups.
- Coordinated readiness reviews for Antenna levels ranging from components to subsystems.
- Supported Root Cause investigations and Corrective Action Boards. Implemented Lessons Learned and best practices into developing and ongoing Antenna projects which reduce the cost of rework within the manufacturing organization.

Mechanical Engineer

Lockheed Martin - Newtown, PA - April 2005 to October 2007

Designed feed supports and components for Sirius 4 and VINASAT satellite customer.

- Regularly interacted and coordinated with Quality Control, Operations, Manufacturing, Electrical engineering and survivability to see design through to completion.
- Responsible for creation and implementation of engineering change orders.
- Worked closely with outside vendors on specifications and schedule for completion of spacecraft components.
- Performed project management support for SBIRS government satellite.

Project Engineer

The Whiting-Turner Contracting Company - Towson, MD - October 2004 to March 2005

Responsible for night shift supervision of (2) major projects, New Jersey State Aquarium in Camden, NJ and National Aquarium in Baltimore, MD.

- Managed and interacted with several outside subcontractors with expertise in a wide range of fields such as masonry, site work, specialties, weatherproofing, hollow metal and overhead doors and carpentry.
- Performed takeoff from blueprints provided by architect and coordinated transfer of information between subcontractors and architects.

EDUCATION

Masters of Business Administration

Villanova University - Villanova, PA December 2012

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Gannon University - Erie, PA May 2004